<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style.xsl" ?>
<root>
    <profile>
        <name>Leonardo Giovanni Scur</name>
        <picture href="assets/me.png">
            Monochromatic photo of a caucasian male in his early twenties,
            slightly overweight, shoulder-length hair tied at the back,
            wearing slightly crooked square-framed glasses and a black T-shirt upon an empty background.
        </picture>
        <introduction>
            Hi! I'm Leonardo, a game programmer who also makes web things in his spare time.
        </introduction>
        <contact name="E-mail"
                 href="mailto:me@kroltan.com"
                 value="me@kroltan.com"
                 kind="identity"/>
        <contact name="LinkedIn"
                 href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kroltan/"
                 value="kroltan"/>
        <contact name="GitHub"
                 href="https://github.com/kroltan"
                 value="kroltan"/>
        <contact name="itch.io"
                 href="https://kroltan.itch.io/"
                 value="kroltan"/>
        <contact name="Ludum Dare"
                 href="https://ldjam.com/users/kroltan/games"
                 value="kroltan"/>
        <contact name="StackOverflow"
                 href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/1045510/kroltan"
                 value="kroltan"/>
        <contact name="Mastodon"
                 href="https://functional.cafe/@kroltan"
                 value="at functional.cafe"/>
    </profile>
    <job company="Prodigy Education"
         title="Software Developer III"
         start="2023"
         id="prodigy2023">
        <summary>
            Multiplayer web game development in TypeScript
        </summary>
        <p>
            Development and maintenance of <a href="https://prodigygame.com">Prodigy Math</a>, a classroom and home-use
            educational math game, using a custom TypeScript-based web game engine.
        </p>
    </job>
    <job cover="assets/pkxd.png"
         company="Afterverse"
         title="Game Software Engineer"
         start="2021"
         end="2023"
         id="afterverse2021">
        <summary>
            Programming for PK XD, a 3D mobile social game with millions of downloads on a large team,
            mostly Unity and C# gameplay programming and software architecture, some Kotlin backend/networking.
        </summary>
        <p>
            Development of user-facing and internal features for PK XD (<a
                href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.movile.playkids.pkxd">Android</a>, <a
                href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pk-xd-explore-the-universe/id1449842729">iOS</a>, <a
                href="https://playpkxd.com/">Desktop</a>),
            a 3D multiplayer social game for kids (think Club Penguin styled after The Jetsons) with >100 million
            downloads. Some of my work on it:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Marking backpack items as favorites for easier access to preferred items;</li>
            <li>Health, score and respawn logic for shooter-based UGC games, from networking, to gameplay, and UI;
            </li>
            <li>
                Significant performance and architectural improvements to the usage of Addressables for loading
                of player-created houses and games;
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            I worked mainly with C# on the Unity game client, but would sometimes dip into the server-side Protobuf
            and Kotlin code when needed. Also worked on the software architecture, fundamental features and tooling
            for unannounced projects.
        </p>
        <p>
            Built an ECS-inspired architecture to standardize the local access as well as network synchronization of
            interactive game objects for an unnanounced project, allowing for faster development of networked
            gameplay features. Using said architecture, implemented an object picking menu for touchscreen interactions
            between player and world in third-person.
        </p>
    </job>
    <job title="Game Development Analyst"
         company="DOT Digital Group"
         start="2018"
         end="2021"
         id="dot2018">
        <summary>
            Educational and corporate game development on a small team using Unity. VR, AR, mobile
            and web games and simulations, participating in the entire project timeline, from concept to deployment.
        </summary>
        <p>
            Design, planning, and development of educational games, corporate training games, and simulators in
            Unity.
        </p>
        <p>
            Worked on a variety of projects that used various unconventional technologies such as virtual,
            augmented, and mixed reality, as well as targeting mobile and web platforms.
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>A VR harvesting combine simulator, with an accurate replica of a real machine's control panel and
                harvesting process. The goal was to offer a practice environment for new operators;
            </li>
            <li>Web-based games for embedding into e-learning platforms. Both low-spec 3D, and 2D games;</li>
            <li>Various quiz style games for mobile and web, such as <a
                    href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=br.com.sistemafaeg.agrinho">Programa
                Agrinho</a>, a fully-offline mix of quizzes and activities for rural school children;
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            Architected and developed an in-house tool for authoring and publishing visual novel/interactive fiction
            games, using a node-based workflow with a graphical editor written in Unity. This allowed non-technical
            writers to build the entire plot of a game in a single tool, while the technical team implemented any
            specific gameplay modules required by each individual project.
        </p>
    </job>
    <job company="Lagoasoft"
         title="Web Developer"
         start="2016"
         end="2018"
         id="lagoasoft2016">
        <summary>
            Frontend web development, both maintenance and greenfield, Knockout, Angular, React.
        </summary>
        <p>
            Front-end web development and maintenance of Knockout, Angular, and React web applications.
            Implemented designs created by internal and external teams as well as implemented connections to REST
            web APIs.
        </p>
        <p>
            Later, leading development in React web applications as well as a React Native mobile application.
        </p>
    </job>
    <job company="Chaordic"
         title="Web Developer Intern"
         start="2013"
         end="2015"
         id="chaordic2013">
        <summary>Front-end Angular development, CSS, some Python backend work.</summary>
        <p>
            Some reasonably diverse experiences: mostly front-end AngularJS development, implementing layouts and
            functionality for dashboards and adminstration panels.
        </p>
        <p>
            Secondarily, I also helped maintain back-end data transformation and transfer scripts in Python,
            interacting
            with AWS features. As well as some maintenance and monitoring in Docker-based infrastructure.
        </p>
    </job>
    <project cover="assets/wizsnooks.png"
             name="Wizsnooks"
             id="wizsnooks">
        <p class="summary">Game Design and Development, Ludum Dare roguelike+snookers mashup</p>
        <p>An entry to the famous <a rel="noopener noreferrer"
                                     href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/41/wizsnooks">Ludum Dare
        </a> game
            jam. Can be <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://whalesandgames.itch.io/wizsnooks">played in your
                browser</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            This is a very creative dungeon crawling game, with a very important twist: You play as a cueball, and
            fight through pool/billiards rules or RPG-style attacking! This game features a complete loot and
            inventory system, and a infinite game session with over 20 items to be found and 15 levels to explore!
        </p>
        <p>
            I acted as a developer together with an artist, and a musician. Also designed the itch.io page for the
            game.
        </p>
    </project>
    <project cover="assets/farmfortress.png"
             name="Farm Fortress 2"
             id="farmfortress">
        <p class="summary">Game Design and Development, 3D Modeling, Ludum Dare low poly strategy/"factory" game</p>
        <p>
            An entry to the famous
            <a
                    rel="noopener noreferrer"
                    href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/45/farm-fortress-2">
                Ludum Dare
            </a>
            game jam. Can be
            <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://kroltan.itch.io/farm-fortress-2">
                played in your browser</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            A resource production chain game where you manage a food production chain, from planting wheat to
            selling bread!
        </p>
        <p>
            I acted as sole author, performing all of the game design, programming, 2D and 3D art.
        </p>
    </project>
    <project cover="assets/wooficechair.png"
             name="Woofice Chair"
             id="wooficechair">
        <p class="summary">Game Development, Ludum Dare wave survival game about cute dogs versus buff animals</p>
        <p>
            An entry to the famous
            <a
                    rel="noopener noreferrer"
                    href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/47/woofice-chair">
                Ludum Dare
            </a>
            game jam. Can be
            <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://whalesandgames.itch.io/woofice-chair">
                played in your browser</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            This is a goofy wave survival game where you play as one of 3 excellent dogs stuck on a spinning office
            chair! Your objective is to defend the dog park from invading body-building cats, pidgeons and
            squirrels, while keeping top angular speed!
        </p>
        <p>
            I acted as a developer together with another developer, an artist, and a musician.
        </p>
    </project>
    <project cover="assets/joulethief.png"
             name="Joule Thief"
             id="joulethief">
        <p class="summary">Game Design and Development, Ludum Dare arcade "mob kiting" game</p>
        <p>
            An entry to the famous
            <a
                    rel="noopener noreferrer"
                    href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/39/joulethief-charge-your-phone">
                Ludum Dare
            </a>
            game jam. Can be
            <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://https://kroltan.itch.io/joule-thief">
                played in your browser</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            This game is about some guy whose phone's battery is low, and he must break into houses and venues to
            steal electricity from the outlets. But the police is after him for being a Joule Thief!
        </p>
        <p>
            I acted as a developer together with an artist, and a musician. Also designed the itch.io page for the
            game.
        </p>
    </project>
    <project cover="assets/supersellout.png"
             name="Super Sellout"
             id="supersellout">
        <p class="summary">Game Development, Ludum Dare game about user-defined difficulty</p>
        <p>
            An entry to the famous
            <a
                    rel="noopener noreferrer"
                    href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/43/super-sellout">
                Ludum Dare
            </a>
            game jam. Can be
            <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://whalesandgames.itch.io/super-sellout">
                played in your browser</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Monetization Man is a modern superhero with modern minor internet celebrity issues: he needs money! Take
            on absurd sponsorships and try to save as many people as you can!
        </p>
        <p>
            I acted as a developer together with another developer, an artist, musician and a level designer.
        </p>
    </project>
    <project cover="assets/troposphir.png"
             name="Troposphir"
             id="troposphir">
        <p class="summary">Reverse Engineering, Native and Web Development, UGC platformer game</p>
        <p>
            Community-created alternate server for Atmosphir, a game whose official services was shutdown. Lots of
            reverse-engineering work went into it, resulting in a (honestly very messy) PHP codebase. In my defense,
            I was 15!
        </p>
        <p>
            We also implemented a surrounding ecosystem for users:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Multiplatform game launcher that automatically updates the game, in C# and GTK#</li>
            <li>
                Landing page to inform new users, which eventually was bestowed the official domain name by the
                game's erstwhile developers.
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            I acted as a developer and project manager for the server project, as well as helping conceptualize and
            develop other tools related to the game. The team size varied over time, but was at its most composed of
            4 people.
        </p>
    </project>
</root>